Today, I'm going to explain the
different levels of building your own AI
second brain. You can see here we have a
visual of three very different types of
data. This one is where we have our
context really starting to form and
we're starting to see some relationships
and we're starting to see some different
nodes and entities form. And then as we
continue to scale this up, add more
knowledge, more knowledge, more
relationships, we start to get something
that looks a little bit more like this
where we have clearly different clusters
and inside of all of these nodes we can
see how they relate to each other. And
then over here we're taking all of those
relationships a step farther and we're
able to then start to see how everything
really pieces together rather than just
having files that sort of link back to
each other. This is relationship
mapping. And so really the idea of an AI
second brain has blown up because we're
all trying to get as much information
out of our heads into our systems as
possible. That's the true value. Your
moat is your data, it's your IP. But the
process of organizing that into a system
so that you can use it with a bunch of
different AI models and so that it can
actually recall things in a way that
makes sense rather than just
hallucinating or spending a bunch of
your time and tokens trying to look
through everything. That's the issue. So
clearly all of this is my real data and
this is what the actual project looks
like. It is my Hercule project. I have a
bunch of folders and files here and at
the end of the day that's basically all
it is. It is markdown files that are
organized in a way that I understand and
that my agents understand. And so yes,
I'm going to walk you guys through what
I have here and how it works, but I also
have this other project where I'm going
to show you if you're starting from
scratch or if you feel like maybe you're
in between level two and three, how we
can actually look at the differences and
what it might look like to scale up your
own systems and start to add context in
different ways. So super excited to dig
into this today and I don't want to
waste any of you guys' time, so let's
just start looking at these five levels
and how they differ. All right, so every
level of a Claude Code second brain and
I'm going to be obviously kind of
referring to Claude Code a lot, but keep
in mind this can be used with any AI
model. I use my second brain all the
time with Codex as well. I use it with
Hermes Agent. This can be used by
different agent harnesses because it's
just files and folders. So, what is the
actual job of a second brain? A lot of
people probably define this differently,
but the way that I think about it is
that it's a place for me to save notes,
meeting recordings, ClickUp threads,
stuff like that. I can save it there,
and then it helps me basically ingest it
and get it into the right spots so that
it can actually find it later. And so
that's really the thing to think about
is can your agent find it again, and
could you find it again? Because if the
answer is no, then you probably don't
have the right routing or folder
architecture set up, which is what I'm
here to talk about today. And one other
sort of mindset thing that I want to get
out there before we dive into these five
levels is that
you kind of have to work backwards. You
want to reverse engineer based on the
question. So this will start to make
more sense as we get into it, but really
what you should be thinking about is how
do I want to use this data in the
future? Because how it's going to be
accessed and recalled determines the way
that you put it in in the first place.
For example, a basketball hoop and a
basketball. We know what shape the hoop
is, and we know that the ball needs to
go through. So why would we ever design
the ball to be a giant square? Because
it just wouldn't fit through the hoop,
so that would make no sense. So you need
to start with the end in mind a little
bit. Once again, I will show you exactly
what I mean by that as we continue on.
Because remember, we're trying to get to
the point where your second brain knows
everything about your business, about
you, your relationships. It knows
everything to the point where
it probably can recall stuff better than
you can because it has a better memory,
and it can search through things way
faster than you can. So we've got five
different levels to talk about, and they
each kind of have different questions.
So level one is, can you find the file
or the info by looking for an exact word
or name? Level two is, can you pull
everything on a certain topic together?
Level three is, I search for different
words than I wrote, so semantic search,
you're searching for meaning rather than
an exact word match. And then trace
relationship chains. Can you ask about
topic X, and then trace that all the way
back to topic A? And then level five is
just kind of making this whole second
brain thing super autonomous to the
point that you don't even have to think
about it. And by the way, this isn't me
saying that number five is best. I have
some arguments about why I do not
currently sit on level five. The point
I'm trying to make here is each level is
different and you want to find the
simplest level or the lowest level that
actually fits your needs. If you don't
have a pain point in your system, then I
don't really think there's a need to go
experiment or develop a new sort of, you
know, architecture. If there's not pain,
then why create more? Okay, so level one
is pretty simple and this is where you
always start. So you start with a
claw.md or if you're using codex or
something, you would start with an
agents.md.
But you start with a claw.md which is
kind of, you know, that gets loaded up.
That's almost like the system prompt for
that session for that project. And then
you've just got a bunch of folders and
files. But the key part there is the
claw.md is kind of treated as a router.
So yes, you've got some, hey, this is
your role, here is what's important, but
you also have routing rules. If you ever
need to find information about me
personally, look in this folder. If you
need information about our quarter one
priorities, look in this folder. Because
if you've ever had a point where you ask
Claude to do something and then it asks
you, hey, can you give me more info? I
don't know what you're talking about,
but you know there's files and folders
in your project, then you probably just
didn't give Claude the knowledge to go
look there. It's not just going to go
search your entire code base
automatically. I mean, you wouldn't want
it to do that cuz it's going to waste
your time and your tokens. So if it
doesn't know if something lives
somewhere, then it's probably not going
to be able to find it. So when this is
properly set up, you will stop having to
re-explain things, you will talk to it
and it will just know where to go look
and why. But the problems with this is
that if it grows too big, it can start
to get messy and feel ignored. And this
is typically more of like an exact words
type of search depending on the way that
you route. So if I open up my um example
project here, let's open up level one.
So in level one, what you can see,
pretend this is its own Claude project,
we've got a claw.md. So let me click
into that. We can see here it says, this
file loads automatically every time you
open Claude Code in this folder. It is
the one file that tells the AI who you
are, how you work, and where things
live. At level one, this file plus a few
folders is your entire second brain. So,
here's kind of like that basic
knowledge, and then right here, it's
this simple, where things live. In the
context folder, always true background
about you and how you work, read this
first. Projects, decision log, and
that's basically it. So, right here you
can see there's a context folder, we
have an about me file, which you could
grow. We have stack and conversations
file. We have decisions, so this is a
decision log where you can have your
Claude at MD always append new decisions
and dates whenever you make a big change
to your project or to your life or to
your business. And then we have
projects, so this is where you could
have a markdown file or even folders
within the projects for all of your
ongoing projects, all of your ongoing
clients, whatever it is, however you
want to organize it, that's where you
can have some projects. And you can even
start to organize these things by dates
if you want. So, if you want to just
have one that's for like May, and then
you have all of those stuff, and you
have one for June. The thing that I
really want to stress here with level
one, and the thing that I answer a lot
in my community in the comments, is that
there is not yet a standard way that has
been proven the best way to set up your
projects or your second brain besides
some of the most common things like your
contexts and your Claude at MD and your,
you know, whatnot. But, the point I'm
trying to make there is
don't see what I do and think that
that's the right way, or see what
someone else you watch does and think
that that's the only right way.
All that matters is
do you have proper routing in place, and
does it make sense to you, and does it
make sense to your AI? Okay, so let's
say I have my Hercule project right
here, and I need to find something in
here, but I can't ask AI for some
reason. What I need to find is easy
because I understand the drill downs.
You know, I understand my base folders,
and let's say I'm looking for the HTML
slide deck I built for my
ranking Claude code features video. I
would come into here and I say, okay, I
know that's a project, so I'll go there.
Within my projects, I've got another
project for YouTube videos, I'll open
that up. And now I know I made this
video right here, May 30th Claude code
top 50 features. In here, I have the
actual tier list deck, and when I open
that up, now I have the slide deck, and
not only can I find it easily, but my
agent can find it because it all makes
sense and I have routing rules. Real
quick, guys, if you're watching this
video, you're probably interested in
building your own AI operating system.
Lucky for you, I have a full free course
on that in my free school community. The
link for that is down in the
description. Join the free school
community, hop in here, take the 7-day
challenge, build your own AI operating
system, and apply these principles into
building your second brain, which will
make your AI operating system even more
powerful. So, link's in the description.
Let's get back to the video. Awesome.
Okay, so that is how you start. Now, as
you move up to level two, you might be
able to start to work in some things
like the LLM Wiki, which is what I've
got set up for a few different things.
This is the whole Karpathy LLM Wiki,
which I did make a full video about if
you want to check that out. I'll tag
that right up here. But, this is when
you start to have more files and and
they start to take a bit of a different
shape, and you want to organize them
together in a bit of a different way.
So, it could be really good for
researching all on a certain project. It
could be really good for, you know, a
few of the ones that I've got set up is
my YouTube transcripts all live in their
own Wiki. I've got all of like my
meeting transcripts that live in their
own Wiki. So, for example, this is the
Obsidian view of my Wiki for all of my
YouTube video transcripts. You can see
here if I go to Wiki, you can see
there's main concepts like agentic
workflows, AI coding market, context
window. And all of these in here start
to relate back to other tools and
concepts and videos and stuff like that.
So, we've got the sources, we've got
platforms, we've got um context
management techniques. And all of this
was auto-created by our Claude code when
I told it to ingest this YouTube
transcript into our Wiki. So, I'm not
going to dive super super deep into all
of this right now, but definitely check
out that YouTube video I linked. Now,
what else is cool about this is this
transcript Wiki actually lives within my
main Herc 2 project. So, here's Herc 2.
If I go right here to Other Worlds, and
then I go down to YouTube OS, and I
click into the transcript Wiki right
here, this is what we were just looking
at in Obsidian. We could see the
concepts, we could see the comparisons,
we could see the sources, techniques.
This is what we were looking at in
Obsidian. So, all Obsidian is is it
basically just visualizes your markdown
files. You see here, wiki, concepts,
comparisons, techniques. This is what we
were just looking at. All we get now is
we just get a visual view of all that.
And so, the reason I wanted to bring
that up as well is because I think a lot
of people obviously get pretty
infatuated by that visual view. And
obviously, I started the video with that
because I think that's what hooks a lot
of people in. But, all that really
matters is can your system grab that and
give it to you? If you are a visual
person and you really want that view,
then by all means, install Obsidian and
set it up. It's super easy. But, I'm
saying that you don't always need that
visual layer if it's not beneficial to
you. I hardly ever open Obsidian, just
to be honest, because I know that it all
lives here and I know that my second
brain and my OS can find all of that.
So, anyways, in level two here, let's
look at this. It's very similar in shape
to level one. It's just building on top
of it because now we have our claw.md,
which starts to route to some other
things because it routes to the wiki and
it still routes to contexts, projects,
decisions, but it's also routing to
references and memory.md. So, we're just
starting to add a bit more of these
routing rules inside of the claw.md.
We can grow the context, we can grow the
decisions, we can grow projects and
references, and we can also start to get
this idea of memory. And what's really
cool about this is you can turn on auto
memory in Claude Code. And the AI will
basically start to write this file and
update it on its own. So, you don't have
to think about it. If you come in here
and you do \slash} memory, it'll say
auto memory on or off. And if it's off,
if you want to turn that on, just turn
it on. And now, one thing to think about
is I mentioned earlier that we want to
make our second brains tool agnostic.
And this is one thing that's pretty
specific about Claude Code is it uses
claw.md and it uses this memory.md and
it keeps that updated on its own. So, if
you wanted to move this over to Codex,
what you would do is you would first of
all transition your claw.md. You'd make
a copy of it called agents.md. As you
can see here in my Herc 2, I've got my,
if I scroll down, claw.md right here,
and then I've got agents.md right here.
And they're essentially the exact same
file. Just so Codex can read this one
and Claude code can read this one. But
because Claude code keeps that auto
memory, all you need to do is make sure
you have that memory.md file and just
tell Codex, "Hey, by the way, for
memories, look in our memory.md file."
It's all about the routing there.
Anyways, just felt like that was
important to throw out. But at a certain
point, when you have these, you know,
wikis, they do start to degrade a little
bit. Because what's what's great about
them is that they have indexes, right?
So, when your AI starts to look in the
wiki, it knows, "Okay, if the user's
asking about a genetic workflow, I'm
probably going to start here. And then
from here, I'm going to drill down and
read this to see what else is important
to them." Maybe they're asking about the
WATC framework, and then I can drill
into that. And maybe from there, I need
to learn a little bit more about the
Claude at MD system prompt, and then I
will drill into that. So, there are
relationships here a little bit, but
this isn't the same as like semantic
relationships or knowledge graph
relationships that have more meaning.
This is more about just actually
following a trail and reading the page
in its entirety. And I'll be fully
honest with you guys,
I pretty much sit my entire PERC 2
project in this level, in level two.
Because this has been working really
well for me. Like I mentioned earlier, I
haven't felt a pain yet big enough to
switch over to level two. And here's
what I meant by that. My wiki has links,
isn't that a knowledge graph? Not
exactly. Because this doesn't have
connections of how they are related,
like this is endorsed by this or this
has cron to here. These just have
connections because it's like a a see
also. It's like backlinks. So, they're
very similar, and yes, they can achieve
a similar effect, but it's still a
little bit different. Anyways, let's
take a look at level three, which is
where you start to do things like
semantic search. Whether you do that in
Obsidian, whether you do that with Pine
Cone or Supabase, however you start to
grab the actual semantic search,
that is what level three is. And so,
just as a quick visual for you guys,
let's take a look at this quadrant
cluster of images. So, every one of
these vector points is an image. And
what we see in here is the payload is
stuff like the file name, the URL, the
name of the author or the artist, and
the URL. But, we don't actually see like
what's in the image. We don't get a
description. So, what we have to do is
we have to organize these images by
meaning or by similarity. So, when I
open up this graph and we start to
visualize the stuff here, what you see
is that we have this main image, these
owls, these kind of like I don't even
know. Um it's a very trippy style, like
hallucinogenic style. Anyways, then this
one is kind of similar, right? It's got
those colors, it's got the paints. This
one is also similar, but they're not the
same. They just share similarities. And
as we start to expand these more and
more, we can start to get into different
styles. So, this one has like some
creepy eyes and mushrooms or whatever.
This one is kind of more down that
fantasy lane. And as we start to build
out more of these relationships and
meanings, we can expand and grow away
from them. And so, Quadrant really just
gives you a visualization here. I mean,
it's a it has clusters and vector store.
But, [snorts] the reason I pulled this
up as a demo is just because we start to
see the actual relationships form here
based on meaning. And that's what's
important about semantic search is that
we're no longer doing keyword matching,
we're searching based on meaning. So,
here in my YouTube transcript second
brain, if I go to the smart lookup over
here, this is very different from just
the regular search. So, for example, if
I search here for um
feedback, let's say. We're actually
doing a match on the word feedback, and
it's only showing me where that word
actually appears inside of our second
brain. But, if I come over here in the
smart lookup and I search for feedback,
we are getting matches that have things
in here that mean feedback. So, live
test results, cloud code skills, which
was uh talking about evaluations and
stuff. So, there's a big difference
between keyword matching and semantic
search, you know, similarity matching.
This one over here is saying X equals X,
and this one is saying X is similar to
X, Y, and Z. And so, this all just goes
back to vector databases. I've talked
so, so much about vector databases, so
I'm not going to dive super deep in.
I've got so many resources on my
channel. But basically, what it is is we
take a document, so let's just say
YouTube transcript, we chunk it up, and
then each chunk is ran through an
embeddings model. And the embeddings
model puts that chunk of text onto like
a three-dimensional space where space is
related to meaning. And so it decides,
okay, this chunk is about a company, so
we're going to put it up here. This
chunk is about finances, so it's going
to go here. And we start to see these
vectors form near other similar vectors.
Now, do you guys remember how I said
earlier, like you want to think about
how is the data going to be used? What
type of questions are you going to ask?
This is a reason why that's so
important. So think about this. Let's
say I put my meeting transcript of March
5th meeting into my second brain. And I
put those in as, you know, vectorized
chunks. So let's say when I vectorize
that meeting, we actually get, you know,
like
20 chunks. It actually creates 20
chunks, or however many that is. And
then when I say, "Hey, Mr. AI agent, can
you summarize the meeting on March 5th?"
It will basically search for March 5th
meeting summary, and it will pull chunks
that are similar to March 5th meeting
summary. And then even if it gets the
right chunks, it's going to only
summarize those five chunks. It's not
able to look at the entire meeting
summary, or sorry, like meeting
transcript in entirety. So it doesn't
really know a summary. It might be
missing a lot of key information. Now
yes, there are things you can start to
play with there like metadata and other
things like that to make these results
better, but at the end of the day,
people kind of assumed that a vector
database was some magic solution where
it could always pull back what you need,
but that is very false. And I mean,
think about it like this. Let's say we
have a table, and we say, "Hey, which
week did we have the highest sales?"
Okay, the agent looks for highest sales,
it maybe grabs this chunk outlined in
gray of data, and then it looks at,
"Okay, week six here was the highest
sales, so that must be the answer." But
in reality, you can see week 14 was
higher, week 19 was higher. So when you
need something that has actual full
context,
then you can't do the vector database
chunking. That's where you'd rather just
have a markdown file of March 5th, and
then all this agent would have to do is
read that entire markdown file and then
give you a summary. And that's just
going to be more accurate. So, in this
project, if we open up level three, you
can see it's very similar because you
can still have context files, decision
files, you can still have all that, and
then you might identify, "Okay,
actually, this one specific unit of my
business, maybe my YouTube transcripts,
maybe I want just that to be a vector
database, but I still want my context
and my projects and my decisions to be
markdown files."
So, another point I'm trying to make
here is
just because you have a second brain,
and just because you have a massive, you
know, folder here with a bunch of
folders and files, doesn't mean that the
whole folder needs to be one style. It
doesn't mean that everything needs graph
rack. It doesn't mean that everything is
just LLM Wiki. It means that you're able
to decide, based on the type of data and
the way you use it, how can you
structure this specific folder in the
way you want it. So, here we have a
vector index folder, and we click on the
house search works. It works by
chunking, embedding, search, hybrid,
re-ranking. There's some things you can
get really, really nitty-gritty on when
it comes to semantic search. But what
vector retrieval is really, really good
at is looking at tons and tons of data,
typically just like a lot of text, and
when you need a very specific answer,
something that's very similar. So, if
you had a thousand rules that you needed
to store, and you basically said, "Hey,
um can you remind me what rule 17 was?"
That might be a really good use case for
vector search because it's able to
search for rule 17, pull in those
chunks, and just give you a little
snippet because it would be a waste of
time and tokens for your agent to read
the entire markdown file of all 1,000
rules if you just needed rule 17. So,
that's kind of the difference there.
Like I said, I've got so many videos on
vector stuff on my channel, but really
you could say, "Hey,
to your cloud code agent, I have this
data. Here's how I want to use it. Do
you think this would be better for now
as markdown files, or should I do
semantic search? Like what would
actually make more sense here?" And it
will help walk you through the way that
you should actually set that up. So, now
I hope you guys are starting to
understand why I said, you know, moving
up on or I'm sorry, like moving up on
levels, moving down doesn't necessarily
mean better. It's all about figuring out
what is the pain point with what you're
currently doing and where would a
different level help you out and fix
that pain point. Okay, so now let's take
a look at level four. This is where we
start to get into like knowledge graphs
and relationship graphs, which typically
are going to be the most complex and
sometimes the most expensive as well. If
you're doing it on a certain platform,
you could always use open source
software, but anyways, knowledge graphs.
And I also want to be up front. I've
played with these a lot, but I do not
actually use these on the day-to-day
because I found out just other ways to
use routing files and wikis that fit my
needs. Now, my work is very different
than what a lot of you guys' work may
be. Mine is very project-based and it is
very, you know, content-heavy. I don't
have a massive CRM to manage with a
bunch of different businesses and
clients, you know? And if I did, maybe a
knowledge graph would make a lot more
sense and it probably would. But
typically, the cool part about that is
if you identify that you needed a
knowledge graph, let's say for all your
projects, you needed you wanted to put
all of this in a knowledge graph,
the data probably already exists here.
And that's the thing about building out
these relationships in your knowledge
graph is that the system, whatever
software you use, is typically going to
be pretty good at embedding that and
creating that. But the problem that you
have to solve is you have to give it
enough data. And so, one thing that I
really like to do is I like to have
these brainstorm sessions, as you can
see. And what I do with these brainstorm
sessions is I use a skill called Grill
Me. So, if you see here, I have a skill
called Grill Me, which I originally got
from Matt Pocock. I customize it a
little bit. I'll leave the skill for
Grill Me in my free school community.
The link for that is down in the
description. All you have to do is hop
in here, go to classroom, click on all
YouTube resources, and you can find all
the skills and everything like that. But
the skill, what that does, is it
basically just grills me. It interviews
me relentlessly about a certain topic
and it creates a brainstorm file here.
It only stops when it knows everything
about it. So, if you wanted to start
building up a knowledge graph for all
your clients and businesses, just say
"Grill me about client A. Grill me about
client B. Grill me about business A."
And it would just ask you questions and
you can feed it files. You can give it
stuff. You can feed it in transcripts.
You can feed it in, you know, contracts,
whatever it is. And that's how you can
start to form a lot of data.
Hey guys, me again. Real quick, I'm
editing this video and I realized that I
needed to throw out one thing here,
which is that obviously, if you're
putting all of this data and you're
sending it all to Anthropic, to Claude
models, then
that's not private. So, if you feel
comfortable with that, that's fine. I am
putting a lot of my data in there and it
is my business stuff and
that's what I'm doing. But, if you don't
feel comfortable with that or you, you
know, don't want to send client data, of
course you don't, then maybe you want to
do that through open-source models and
maybe Claude code isn't where you have
the second brain that has every single
piece of information about you and your
business and your client's business. So,
the point I'm trying to make here is
just this is what I'm doing. I'm
obviously aware of the fact that my data
goes to Anthropic when I process it
through Claude. And if you guys are
doing that, then you should also be
aware of that. But, there are other
options if you can't do that. So, I
wanted to throw that out there. I am
planning to make a ton of videos here
soon about local AI and open-source
models and all this stuff cuz it's a
really, really exciting space that I
think is going to start becoming bigger
and bigger. So, yeah, keep that in mind.
Back to the video. I think sometimes
that's a misconception about how I got
here and how people build their own AI
OS or second brain is that
they think the problem is the system not
retrieving it great, which sometimes it
is, but sometimes it seems like the
bigger problem is getting everything out
of your brain into the system. So,
before you blame AI, take a look at your
folders and files and say, "Is this
actually holistic? Is this Does this
have all the nuance that I have in my
brain?" Anyways, from there, when you
open up level four, you can see that
it's it's, you know, very similar still.
We're just adding on a few things. You
can see here we've added an agents.md,
which is the exact same as the
claude.md. And what else is cool is you
can literally just reference inside of
your claude.md at agents.md and then you
can delete all this because this
basically just like injects that file
into here. But I just wanted to show
that. But anyways, you can see we're
still following the same principles. We
have a wiki. We've also added a
knowledge graph layer. We've still got
the same where things live with the
routing with all these just regular
folders and boring markdown, but boring
is beautiful. You can see that our
memory is still here. It's starting to
grow, and we just keep building on top
of this. So what one thing we added here
as you can see was our knowledge graph
folder. And so what happens here is we
get different entities, right? So like
we can see okay Jordan is a person. Acme
is a company. And then we can start to
form relationships between all these
things. So Jordan works at Acme. Acme is
endorsed by Postpilot. Postpilot is a
competitor of Cadently. And it starts to
build out not only these entities, but
it shows you how they're all related.
And so that's why when I said that I
really like using, you know, this um
what's it called? LLM Wiki is because I
have enough of that feel of all these
relationships because I've put so much
time and effort into ingesting these in
the right way and giving it context. The
thing about this one is that it has to
read every single file it wants. Maybe
it was looking at AI video production
and all it needed to know was
ElevenLabs, it still would have read
this entire file first. And so that's
where sometimes the knowledge graph is
actually more lightweight in that sense.
And this is the example I showed at the
beginning of the video where we have
Lightrag. And forgive me, I'm going to
have to blur some of this stuff out
because this is like legitimately my
entire second brain in our business. But
as I really zoom in here and this kind
of slows down my computer because
there's so much. But what you'll notice
is that we actually start to get
relationships. I probably shouldn't have
done this with so much data, but you can
see like we have this collaborates with
that. We have this builds that. And so
if I really started to open up all of
these little
you know, circles, we could see what was
going on and how they're all related. We
could see that our 7-day AI challenge it
was provided from YouTube. It connects
to the onboarding process of AIS Plus.
It was developed by Aiden. And so we can
basically follow around these
relationships, as you see. And even
though it's pretty much the same data
that you see here in Obsidian, we're not
getting that same level of relationships
between these different entities. So,
anyways, if you guys want to see, you
know, a full breakdown video on
something like Logseq or um Graphir or
all the other solutions that there are
out there for more of a knowledge graph
relationship graph, then let me know.
But, that is kind of the difference
there. So, if you don't need those sort
of relationship chains, and you're not
worried about that semantic type of
relationships, then you probably don't
need to use something like a knowledge
graph. And then, level five, we have
more of the always-on Brain OS, and
something like Gbrain. Garry Tan, CEO of
Y Combinator, he created this thing
called Gbrain, which pairs really well
with G stack. But, Gbrain is kind of the
idea of everything we've talked about
here. Wikis, routing, relationships,
tools. But, Gbrain has kind of that
always-on element, because it is like
constantly syncing and refreshing
memories and adding more stuff. So,
adding in Gbrain to something like a
Hermes agent would be really, really
good. You could still do it in cloud
code, but you'd have to handle those
crons and get all that stuff set up,
which is why I don't currently run
Gbrain at the moment, but I have been
playing around with it with my Hermes
agent. So, anyways, the point here is
that it's very similar to everything
else we've just talked about. It's just
having that auto-updating feel, more of
the autonomous, always-on feel.
But, I will say, another thing that I
kind of that kind of scares me about
that is you have this whole dilemma of,
you know,
when do you have too much context? And
when does it get to the point where it's
actually doing more damage than it's
doing good? And the reason I bring that
up is because I am in complete control
of what my second brain ingests. I will
run a skill to go grab all of my meeting
transcripts from the week. I will say,
"Hey, here's something. Help me figure
out like how many brains are about this,
and then let's ingest it together." And
for me, I really like being in that
control, because in my mind, there's a
big difference between a few types of
data. If you guys remember in my like AI
OS videos, I've talked about the four
C's. So, context, connections,
capabilities, and cadence. And for the
second brain, I mainly think about it as
just these first two. So, context and
connections. And so, when I think of
context, that's stuff like, you know,
what my business has done. So, if I come
into here, into my my second brain, and
you can see here if I go to
um up at OTAs. So, OTAs are basically
just our projects for the quarter. And
so, here I can see all the Q1 ones,
right? I can look at all those and I can
click at them and see decisions that
we've made in the statuses. And I can
also see Q2 OTAs. So, I can see what's
going on here. And my second brain's
able to see that because that has been
basically those are locked in decisions.
This is what we're doing this quarter,
and then I'm updating the statuses of
that stuff. So, that's like context.
That's what's going on in the business.
But when it comes to connections, if I
go back to this, this is more of like
the real data that isn't as evergreen.
This is stuff that changes. This is like
Slack threads. This is emails. This is a
customer data. And that type of data you
don't want to ingest into a second brain
because that's just noise then. Then you
have to go back every month and like
delete old stuff. So, the way that I
like to think about my actual second
brain is stuff that I'm not going to
delete. This is stuff that is like,
okay, in a year, will it be good for me
to have this memory in here? Yes.
Otherwise, it's just adding noise. So,
when you're adding data into your
project, think about it like the context
and connections. Think about if this is
kind of like more evergreen, holistic
data, or if this is more things that are
going to change next week. So, you
probably shouldn't pull it in, but you
should make sure that your second brain
has access to go grab it. So, that way
if I said to my second brain, "Hey, can
you just take a look real quick at what
John and I were talking about last week
about, you know, OTA number seven?" It
would first go to our OTA file, and it
would search through there and it it
would try to find it there. If it
couldn't find it there, it would look
through the Wiki and it would look
through meeting transcripts and see what
we talked about there. And if it
couldn't find it there, it would finally
go to ClickUp itself, pull real data in
from me and John's conversations, and
see if the answer lived there. And so,
that in my mind is still a second brain
because I'm able to ask a vague
question, and the second brain knows
exactly where to look in what order to
find that real-time data, and then give
me back the answer that I need. That's
the question I ask myself is, "Does this
thing understand where my data lives and
where to look, and can to give me
accurate answers. So, as far as finding
your level, remember your whole project
doesn't fit into one level. Maybe this
folder's level two, maybe this folder's
level four, maybe this folder's level
three. Here's some things to think
about. If you were re-explaining your
setup and you need to find things by
exact words or files, look at level one.
If you have 30 plus notes and you keep
forgetting what's in them, look at level
two. That's where you sort of like
ingest them and get that wiki with
relationships. If your project is just
completely whiffing on notes that you
know exist and your routing isn't
working, then maybe you want to look for
something more like a semantic search
that doesn't rely on an exact word level
match. If you're looking for
relationships and to be able to follow
chains of questions and thoughts, then
you probably want to look for something
like a knowledge graph. you're running
agents offline and you've got so much
data and you want to sync up a bunch of
Hermes agents together, then you
probably are looking for something like
level five, something like G brain. And
another topic that I get some questions
about, which I'm not going to fully
address in this video, but I will
briefly bring up is the fact that you
are building your own second brain OS.
So are other people on your team. The
next question is, how do you actually
make sure that everyone's data is
syncing together and how do you have
more of like your team second brain?
There's a lot of different ways to solve
that. I think once again, it's not an
issue of, oh, do we use Google Drive or
Notion or GitHub or cloud plugins? I
think the issue to figure out with your
team is how do we actually make sure
that we all have it shift so that this
stuff is actually useful and not just
noise. How do we make sure that process
owners are updating their docs and
syncing their stuff there? How do we
make sure that other people are pulling
from that rather than always just
pinging the same people for questions
and answers all the time? I think the
adoption and the change management
question is the bigger one. The tech and
the way it actually functionally rolls
out is a little bit less. But what I do
know is that you getting set up with
your own first and understanding how it
works, how you should route, how you
should make the decisions of where the
data should live, that's the first
hurdle. You can only solve the team-wide
problem once you feel comfortable about
the way you run it every single day and
then it works for you. That is going to
do it for today. Like I said, you guys
can grab all the skills and everything
that you need from this free community.
The link for that is down in the
description. I will also include the
slide deck if you guys are interested in
flipping through. So, if you guys
enjoyed the video or you learned
something new, please give it a like. It
helps me out a ton. And as always, I
appreciate you guys making it to the end
of the video, and I will see you all in
the next one.
Thanks, guys.